Sun, Sea and Squeaks.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: Chipwrecked is a comedy,
fantasy, family film directed by Mike Mitchell.
Playing around while aboard a cruise ship, the Chipmunks and Chipettes
accidentally go overboard and end up marooned in a tropical paradise.
They discover their new turf is not as deserted as it seems.
Dave, played by Jason Lee.
Ian, played by David Cross.
Zoe, played by Jenny Slate.
Alvin (voice), played by Justin Long.
Simon (voice), played by Matthew Gray Gubler.
Theodore (voice), played by Jesse McCartney.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: Chipwrecked is a 2011 American live-action animated jukebox musical comedy film directed by Mike Mitchell
and written by Jonathan Aibel and Glenn Berger, based on the characters Alvin and the Chipmunks and the Chipettes.
It is the third in the live-action Alvin and the Chipmunks film series.
The film stars Jason Lee, David Cross, and Jenny Slate, with Justin Long, Matthew Gray Gubler, Jesse McCartney, Amy
Poehler, Anna Faris, and Christina Applegate returning to voice the Chipmunks and the Chipettes, respectively.
In the film, playing around while aboard a cruise ship, the Chipmunks and the Chipettes go overboard and end up
marooned in a tropical island, where they discover their new turf is not as deserted as it seems.
Alvin and the Chipmunks: Chipwrecked was released in the United
States on December 16, 2011, by 20th Century Fox.
The film received generally negative reviews from critics, and
grossed $349 million against a budget of $75–80 million.
A fourth film, The Road Chip, was released in 2015.
The film explores themes of sequel, chipmunk, cruise
ship, live action and animation, overboard.
The tone is lighthearted.